

PROFILE

I am an ambitious and determined 23-year-old from Estonia, who loves getting out of his comfort zone in order to meet interesting and like-minded people as well as improve himself in various fields. Alongside a keen interest in tech, I am also very passionate about travelling, sports and music.

SKILLS

Technologies

Python
JavaScript
HTML/CSS
React.js
Git
Haskell
Selenium
SQL

Languages

Estonian
English
Russian
Spanish

CONTACT

- **** +372 53037391
- ■ oravmarkus@gmail.com
- in /markus-orav-6a3639222
- f /markus.orav.3
- @ @oravmarkus

MARKUS ORAV

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEERING INTERN

Amazon | August 2022 - December 2022, Luxembourg

I was part of the EMEA localization team that builds, maintains and operates the systems that localize at scale catalog products from one Amazon marketplace to another.

- Implemented several features for Amazon Private Brands (using Java) and an internal manual submission GUI tool.
- Designed and implemented software updates to the localization system, resulting in improved latency, accuracy and flexibility.

INTERNSHIP / PROJECT

Alliander | April 2022 - June 2022, Remote

Implemented an API (Python with FastAPI) and GUI (TypeScript with Electron) for planning optimal cable routes for new energy infrastructure.

We worked in a team of five using Scrum methodology.

INTERNSHIP

forkNAV | August 2021, Remote

Wrote the test suite for their web app using Selenium Webdriver.

EDUCATION

ENTREPRENEURSHIP (MINOR)

University of Amsterdam | 2023 - 2024, Amsterdam (Netherlands)

As a part of the minor, we are currently creating a startup. Our startup builds Al-based call bots for companies to answer their customer service phone calls.

As the CTO, I am responsible for the product development. Our system is implemented using Python with Flask alongside the OpenAI and Twilio libraries.

COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING (BSC)

Delft University of Technology | 2020 - 2024, Delft (Netherlands) (Projected) GPA: 8.0 (out of 10).

HIGH SCHOOL

Gustav Adolf Grammar School | 2017 - 2020, Tallinn (Estonia) Graduated with a gold medal (all A's).

RFFFRFNCFS

Vincent Roukine, Amazon +33 6 77 77 45 03 roukinev@amazon.lu